[Music]
focus
innovate enabled
ici tan lombard and cnbc tv 18 present
in their risk management award honoring
the new age risk management
practitioners
hello and welcome to this special chat
on risk management
during covet times and my guest is the
managing director and ceo of issa
lombard
mr bhargav das gupta uh mr dos gupta
thank you very much for joining me
it's a bit of an irony that we are
talking about risk management
at a time and in a situation which no
one ever envisaged
who would have thought that we would go
through times like corvid
uh so that's why this chat becomes
particularly important
before i start the questioning with uh
mr dusk i also want to say
that i says hello modern cnbc tv 18
every year
uh conducts a risk management awards
where we try to pick the best companies
in terms of risk management and i mean
in jury does it
so obviously under kobe times this risk
management award becomes particularly
important okay mr agriculture you know
for an insurer in particular
how is this uh situation changing it
should have become more expensive for
you isn't it you should be upping your
premiums isn't it
if you look at what's happened in
different categories of our business
let's say for the corporate segment
where we provide cover for
uh you know natural uh hazards
or fire losses or supply chain
disruption etc
uh traditionally in india most
corporates have been
uh very focused on buying very limited
sets of cover
so if you see the global debate on
insurance is
whether a pandemic risk can be supported
by
insurance industry in india that debate
didn't even happen
because in the in global context most
companies buy what is known as business
interruption covers
so if the if the business is interrupted
for reasons
beyond a fire or a natural catastrophe
uh there is still those covers available
and bought by insurance
by you know the companies in the world
in india know why is those covers the bi
cover do not exist for
uh as we call it non-damage you know bi
is
not linked to a fire uh or a natural
hazard it's something that people don't
buy
so you don't need to have uh you know
anyone uh you know
expecting a claim because this was not
an uh you know fire hazard or a
you know earthquake or a flood right so
the bigger question that we have to
think about
you know the introspect as india is how
do we
think about risk and how do we think
about protecting ourselves uh
beyond the limited way of articulating
our risk that we've been doing in the
past
okay are you trying to sell this idea
then
i mean it's it's a clearly a conceptual
gap
if we haven't even thought of it uh
so are you are you seeing com are you
selling the idea our company is
receptive to it
business interruption risk so the first
point is the reason why
you know if you see the penetration
numbers in india being so low i mean
we are less than half of china when it
looks at penetration we are
uh you know one tenth of last u.s right
uh and if you look at insurance density
that is per capita premium that we
charge we are we earned in india it's
about one tenth of china
so that shows you the kind of gap that
exists
in india and this these are one of the
few reasons so if you look at corporates
one of the challenges that we have is
talking about
uh some of these what may have been seen
as esoteric
covers may not have been seen as
required covers
uh you know unfortunately these things
happen once you know in a while and
really affects your business
so one of the things that we do need to
do and you know as insurance companies
we are very happy to go out and
provide these covers there is a global
market for uh you know protecting
ourselves against this we as an insurer
obviously will buy uh you know covers
from our reinsurance market
but these powers are available and the
question is whether we are
waking up to these reality the second
question is the larger question and this
is a challenge for everyone across the
world is
how do you ensure a pandemic you know
these kind of events happen and you can
pay for these claims but when it happens
for all your customers
then it becomes challenging for anyone i
mean you know you know
entire economy has to come together to
support you know individuals and
businesses
as we've seen in terms of governmental
cash on this thing but can we solve the
problem to some extent
by creating a you know aggregate pool
let's say come together and create a
pandemic pool
with a support from let's say you know
the the government
or the policy because your insurance
model doesn't work for covering everyone
right
in our model we take a small amount of
premium and pay for claims that happen
for a few
if everyone suffers a claim we cannot
support it because the premium is not
enough
so we need some kind of a support so
maybe the time has come for creating a
pandemic pool
with initially with some some amount of
support maybe from taxes
uh to pay for an event like this and
once uh you know this will not happen
overnight
every year so after maybe 10 15 years
the pool will become large enough to
support a pandemic
event like this so yes we can definitely
encourage a movement in that direction
okay
no that's the second concept you are
throwing uh on our lap
in terms of a pandemic pool that's of
course government policy
and that will take time to move because
i think the government really is flooded
with too many things
but just to scratch the point on
business
interruption uh risk management of
business interruption cover has any
conversation started
are at least larger companies
showing any response to the idea
so a lot of large companies do buy uh
damaged link bi
already exactly fire linked or something
yeah some kind of a you know some kind
of physical damage linked
bi that itself wasn't very popular the
big organizations are more progressive
and more risk conscious organizations
were buying it
but increasingly there is a there is a
demand for that and
that's expanding what we still don't
think
about buying and you know as we are
discussing
uh things that are not linked to a
physical damage uh let's say a supply
chain disruption
uh and you know if you see a global uh
supply chain today
something happens you know a fire in one
of the ports in china
uh can have some implications to your
business so those things are still
not very prevalent conversations do
happen some companies do talk about it
but then when the you know these are not
you know cheap covers because
the it happens and even like this it
actually uh
you know is a large payout for the
insurance companies so the prices are
also
uh you know they're not as cheap as some
of the other uh policies
and that's where at times we struggle
pandemic pool has any conversation
started
uh with policy makers in fact idea had
constituted a committee they have given
a report
on on the pandemic pool uh it basically
looks at protecting the uh these smaller
msmes because
thought process is that's a segment that
we can uh
meaningfully and that's a segment that
needs more protection and when we're
trying to solve the
entire uh you know corporate sector
problem it may not be feasible
in the beginning so let's focus on the
on that strata of corporates
and the whole idea was a small
contribution uh
a pool getting created with support of
insurance companies and possibly even
reinsurance companies
but initially with a backstop from the
government because as i said when
100 of the people claim you know as they
would in a pandemic
uh it is not possible for a pool to uh
sustain and support
so at least initial periods uh you'll
need some kind of a
uh you know uh tax support i completely
take your point that there is enough on
the plate of the government
uh you know that you know there is a
limited to the fiscal space
so obviously there has to be some
prioritization and thought process on
what
we focus on at a governmental level but
the concept has been
deliberated and the report is already
out what about individuals
like you know people like me and my
colleagues are you seeing a greater
uh consumer attention to health and
therefore more people
you know queueing up before you any
change in behavior which may mean more
business
or even more uh responsibility for you
in terms of more claims
so the answer is yes to both uh we
did see a lot more interest in uh
health insurance particularly in the
first six seven months of the
of the year of this year where the
concern about the pandemic was
particularly elevated
and we've also seen significant increase
in the number of claims
for the industry particularly the health
side the other point that i want to make
is that you know when it comes to health
insurance
the same point that i made for pandemic
not being
in a sense insurable but as an industry
we took a call that for retail health
customers we will pay for the claim
though
the pandemic was is typically an issue
yeah and
pandemic you know as i said conceptually
it's difficult for us to uh support
uh you know by the basic nature of
insurance
but we said that uh and by the way some
countries even health insurance claims
have not been paid because of pandemic
but we as an industry uh you know took
the initiative we
uh we started we said that we pay the
authority the regulator was correctly
uh very clear and articulated right up
front that even if some company
refuses to pay the clarifact has to be
paid so as an industry i think we've
done done whatever we think we could
have done
at this point the challenge that we
faced is
in terms of the claim side in terms of a
lack of standardization of claims oh
so you know the same similar case you
know somewhere
you know one hospital is charging seven
less some hospitals
two less that's been a challenge you
know you know this uh
you know it has been an issue for a long
time absolutely that's been a
that's been a challenge but otherwise i
think we've kind of uh stepped up to the
plate
is there a tendency either in government
or in this business uh interruption
induction on their large corporates
or the consumer level to say that my god
this is a one in a century thing
i'll just swim across now and not really
bother about making this
something that will come again there is
always that uh you know tendency among
you know all of us
uh and you know the science teachers and
the psychology pieces
that you know people we do not believe
that something bad will happen to us
right
that is a natural human tendency but the
point is that if you let's say
uh you know in india till about three
four years back or four nine years back
the general belief was the india is the
daughter is not a is not
susceptible to natural natural
catastrophes you know we have
earthquakes we don't have as many floods
i think that thinking is you know out of
the window if you see the number of
catastrophic events that we've had in
this country over the last six seven
years almost every year we've had some
pretty severe uh flooding events if not
earthquake
uh similarly if you look at uh as i said
the blacks
type even incident at the economy level
i mean gse was a black swan event right
2008 uh and here in 2020 we are talking
about a pandemic which is probably even
bigger
black swan now did we and that time i
remember in 2008 we talked about this
being 100 year event
so none of us imagine something as large
would happen within
you know 12 years i think people are
beginning to realize that these things
are not
as remote as they all thought and there
is much more awareness
and sensitivity to risk than we had uh
seen in the
in maybe even five six years later let
me take a break i want to come back and
ask you the gen you know you're also a
managing director not just
of an insurance company but generally as
a managing director there are
disruptions to business
so those questions to mr dos gupta on
how business
should approach risk management at a
time of corvette
back in a minute
ici care lombard and cnbc tv 18 presents
india risk management award honoring the
new age risk management practitioners
ici care lombard and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management award honoring the
new age risk management practitioners
welcome back to this special chat with
mr bhargav the manager and
ceo of icsi lombard on
risk management especially during
corporate times
uh mr dasgupta i want to now speak
about how our lives have changed you
know you began this chat by saying it
was so unusual
would we have thought that we will chat
with you connecting from your home
uh in you know remotely until recently
we used to meet
face to face to speak now this has meant
a big leap in digitalization which means
relying on uh you know relying on
internet relying on info tech along with
it comes cyber risk
so just how are you approaching it as
a managing director of a company and
what does this mean in terms of
insurance
can you actually ensure cyber risk
so let me i'll you know talk about the
cyber disaster but let me step back a
bit and talk about
what we are seeing overall right one is
clearly a behavior shift in our
customers
in the past people you know were
comfortable with
some amount of physical services people
were comfortable with
interacting physically with people now
during the covert period we
saw a preference for digital we saw a
preference for contact lists
we also saw organizations reorganize
themselves in terms of you know people
working from home etc
all of these are in our mind uh changes
for
uh the future as well and this is not
just an episodic change
we believe this will transform the way
we uh you know
provide our customers with uh services
uh going ahead
and the way we continue to operate as an
organization so let me just
spend two minutes on the on the customer
just to give you a couple of examples
on the health side since we discussed
health one of the things that we
decided during the pandemic was to allow
two things one was
free health so you can do a doctor
consult uh
on the app uh which is not in the in a
in a sense the service that we were
offering it was it was it was a paid
service for some customers
but given this period we opened up to
all our customers
these tremendous traction and the
positivity around that
that service feature now going ahead we
will not uh continue with it of course
we'll continue with it because it's
a positive for our customers second
thing that we did was
insurance traditionally pays for
hospitalization claims right so you have
to go to the hospital for 24 hours
we started providing home-based care on
a cashless basis
if you reach out to us our service
providers we didn't want to do it on a
reimbursement basis because of
fraud risk but if you reach out to us we
will provide you a cashless service at
home
and customers are very happy with it
because who wants to go to a hospital
when you know there's a pandemic will
this continue we believe this will
continue so these are
just giving a couple of examples of how
we believe customer
uh you know proposition will change and
we as
as an insurance industry need to also
change uh to service our customers
the second point that you made about
cyber uh you know
uh traditionally as insurance companies
or any company
we used to think about the cyber risk in
terms of to mitigate the cyber risk we
used to think a lot about the perimeter
security
uh once people come inside the
organization how strong is our firewall
how their monitoring mechanism uh you
know what is that
you know the alarm system etc but it was
all within the organization
boundaries now suddenly people are
working from home
so you have to completely re-architect
your cyber security architecture to
thinking about the endpoint security as
well
uh and increasingly will be hybrid some
people will be in office some people
will be in
uh at home uh and i think that's really
been another challenge in terms of
re-architecture are
architecting our security architecture
and
increasingly we believe as an insurance
company that the cyber risk is going to
become
uh a larger and larger component of the
risk that all of us
in corporate india have and we need to
protect for those
what has been the ability for you to
process claims remotely i mean uh until
now perhaps uh
you did many of your claims remotely say
uh
you know an accident insurance cover a
vehicle insurance cover
i guess all of you were already prepared
to do it remotely
but now have you been able to migrate
everything to remote
uh have there been people disputing your
assessment of the
uh you know damage vis-a-vis theirs
is remote really working both in terms
of selling insurance
and settling claims you know
we are big believers in digital and
giving power to the customer power in
the hands of the customer and you know
do it yourself diy is really we believe
very empowering
and our experience is whenever customers
process or initiate the process on their
own
uh we see much less disturbance so be it
in terms of issuing policies
uh digitally you know if you have the
email uh you know
which mostly you do i mean in gi
industry you don't have kyc
but customers are willing to share that
with you uh so if you have the email
your policy is available to you
immediately you take a printout in the
physical version where you send it
through
uh you know post or put it there will be
that eight nine percent that will you
know you have rt or written from origin
etcetera and you will not
the the policy document won't reach even
a simplistic level
it is better for the customer coming to
your bigger point on claims
look uh all of us had that capability at
least we had pioneered this uh
you know virtual inspection for uh you
know for
auto damages so uh you took a you you
know on your app you could take a
video it will uh stream real time live
into our claims house
our claims manager would look at it and
give the authorization
that was roughly about 20 25 of our
policies would go through their claims
would go through that process
during the first one or two months of
the pandemic hundred percent went
through that process because there was
no other choice right
you couldn't uh do anything physically
even as we speak
uh that number is you know ranging
somewhere around 50 to 60 percent oh
when the option of going to a physical
inspection process
i see you know significant increase in
terms of the number of people who are
preferring the virtual inspection rather
than physical inspection
are much less actually oh okay okay
actually that leads very nicely to my
last question you know when i spoke with
other company heads
like yourselves about what has pandemic
left behind
on the hr front there was one gentleman
who said
trust you know even after the pandemic
goes
i will trust my employees more until
before the pandemic
we had to have them in line of sight
people worked only when you saw them
working
but now you trust what is your
experience
do you think this trust factor you just
said that you know customer
disputing your claims are actually
falling
so do you think trust is something we
have gained from the pandemic
you know i can my personal belief i
don't know who
told you that about the employee force
uh that is completely my experience as
well
uh the entire management by wondering
about by
overseeing someone looking over
someone's shoulder is
probably think of the past and one of
the
biggest gains that we've had because of
this new way of working of hybrid
working
is i believe one is the trust factor
and organizations have to gear up to
manage uh
you know through trust uh obviously you
trust by
but verify you look at what's happening
but you are implicitly trust your team
in terms of doing their
job and our experience has been
tremendously positive in terms of
how we've seen our employees step up
on this factor and the second i would
argue is a big positive
is i think this this whole flexi working
or digital working actually flattens the
organization and is more inclusive
it's more inclusive in the sense that
today for uh you know
in let's say a corporate office meetings
in the past
not everyone would travel from
everywhere part of the country right
if it's just a one-hour meeting someone
would say okay you know let it be
uh today every stakeholder who's
relevant for that meeting can join
without any effort that's right we can
do large town halls with people in you
know across the country
you know at the drop of a hat right so
there's a lot of positives in terms of
inclusivity and flattening of the
organization
which i believe culturally can be very
positive for organizations that
continue to adapt uh you know or adopt
this way of working
this is a great learning available thank
you very much for a very enriching
conversation
[Music]
ici fair lombard and cnbc tva team
present
india risk management award honoring the
new age risk management practitioners
[Music]
focus innovate
enabled